PRASANTA KUMAR PAUL



kumar.prasantapaul@gmail.com / prasantamuj@gmail.com +91-7795604232, +91-9474835459, Skype: pkpbarakar Purulia road (Survey Building), Post- Barakar, Dist – Burdwan, Pin no- 713324, West Bengal, India

Professional Summary:

A total 1 year 6 Months of experience in Software Testing with good knowledge of SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle), Test Plan, Test Strategies, Black Box Testing, and Software Testing Life cycle in domain areas of Web Applications, Windows Applications. And 2 years + experience as an Assistant Professor.

Education:

- Amity University (Enrolled 2016)
 Pursuing Ph.D. in Data Mining ((CGPA- 9.0 (90%)) out of 10) 1st Div
- •Manipal University (2012-2014)

 Master of Technology (M.TECH) in Software Engineering, CGPA -7.2 (72%)) out of 10) 1st Div
- West Bengal University Of Technology (2008-2012)
 Bachelor of Technology (B.TECH) in Computer Science and Engineering, DGPA- 7.61(75%) out of 10), 1st Div
- •West Bengal council of Higher Secondary Education (2007) XII from Kulti High School, Science, (64% (P, C, M, ES)).1st Div
- West Bengal Board of Secondary Education (2005)
 X from Dishergarh A.C Institution, (73%) 1st Div
- •Nehru Yuva Kendra (2007-2008)
 Advance Computer Application (79%) 1st Div

Work Experience:

- **1.** Assistance Professor at Ramgarh Engineering College, Ramgarh (*Feb 2015-Current*). http://www.technoindiagroup.com/, http://technoindiaramgarh.org/
 - Teaching, Developing course materials, Training materials, Assistant Exam controller, R&D, consultancy etc.
- 2. Software Engineer, ESurveying Softech (India) Pvt. Ltd (July 2014- Dec 2014). http://www.esurveying.net/
 - Manual Testing for Project ESurvey CADD (Civil Drawing Software), Dhruval (ERP-Software).
 - Preparing Test Plan and Script. Load Testing. Defect tracking and reporting, Working on final testing and getting the product approved by the client.
 - Experience in working with a complex project where most of the testing types ware including Functional Testing, System Testing, and Interface Testing.

Internship Experience (During M.Tech)

- Trainee Testing Engineer, ESurveying Softech (India) Pvt. Ltd (July 2013- June 2014), <u>http://www.erachana.net/</u>, <u>http://www.esurveying.net/</u>
 - Manual Testing, Database Testing, Preparing Test Plan, Test Script for Tremplin- Database Application Development Compressed and Vippe (Reporting tool).
 - Developed 5 Important module for Tremplin and Vippe product on dot Net.
 - Testing application with complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC).

Technical Paper Published (3 Papers):

- TREMPLIN Save Time In Every Project in International Journal of Engineering Research & Technology (IJERT), ISSN: 2278-0181, Vol. 2 Issue 9, September - 2013, IJERTV2IS90535
- <u>Tremplin C# Database Application Development Compressed</u> in International Journal Of Engineering And Computer Science (IJECS), IISN: 2319-7242. Volume 2 Issue 11 November 2013.
- <u>A Report on Dhruval Enterprise Resource Planning Solution Implementing Financial Module</u> in International Journal Of Engineering And Computer Science (IJECS), IISN: 2319-7242. Volume 3.

Projects Done (B.Tech):

- Compiler Design, Institute Of Science and Technology, College Project (June-2011-March 2012)
 Involved in Coding and Testing.
- India Travel & Tourism Ardent Durgapur (June-2011- July- 2011)
 Involved in Coding and design Dot Net Platform using Asp.Net.
- Study Forum (Online), NIVT Kolkata (Dec-2010- Jan- 2011)
 Involved in Coding and design. Net Beans IDE using JSP.

IT FORTE:

Testing Knowledge: Black Box, Database, The Web, White Box.

Data Technologies Data Mining, Big Data

Languages: C (Intermediate), Java (Intermediate).

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu-14)
Technologies: JDBC(Basic), Ado.Net (Basic)

Web Server: Joomla(Intermediate), WordPress(Intermediate), Drupal(Basic)

RDBMS: Oracle10g (Intermediate), Microsoft SQL Server 2008(Intermediate), MYSQL

(Intermediate).

Packages: MS Word, MS Excel, Power Point, Access (Expert)-13

Others: ESurvey Cad, ESurvey Section, ESurvey Kml, Esurvey Lisps, Robosoft, AUTO CAD 15.

Conference Attend:

• Smart Tech 2017 Jaipur, INDIA as Author.

Skills & Interests:

Hobbies: Playing Cricket, Net Surfing, and Computer games.

Languages Known: English (SRW), Hindi (SRW), and Bengali (SRW)

Skills: Good Communication & Analytical Skills, Relationship Management, Leadership Skills

Additional Information:

- •Has successfully done Four Week AICTE approved FDP by IIT Bombay on Use of ICT in Education for Online and Blended Learning
- •Ph.D. work- To develop a hybrid algorithm for data mining.
- Good Knowledge in Civil/Surveying Software (ESurvey CADD, AutoPlotter).

Place: Asansol

Date: Signature: Prasanta Kumar Paul